## Jaderson Rodrigues Ilidio

Backend Development (Undergraduate Student)



### Personal details



Jaderson Rodrigues Ilidio



jaderson.rodigues@yahoo.com



+55 (31) 9 8624-5883



Manoel Pinto Str, 70-A, 36.406-003 Conselheiro Lafaiete, Minas Gerais, Brasil.



September 10th, 1987



jadersonrodrigues.com



linkedin.com/in/jaderson-rodrigues-ilidio



github.com/Jadersonrilidio

## Languages

Portuguese

English

Russian

Spanish

## Domain of Programming Languages and Tools

PHP

HTML

### **Profile**

Bachelor's degree in metallurgical engineering at UFOP - Brazil, 03 years of experience abroad doing a Master's, exchange study and work in United States and Russia, currently enrolled in a bachelor of backend development. Possess strong inclination towards computer science field, ouststanding by teamwork expertise, logical reasoning and eagerness for learning. Looking forward to deppen their knowledge in a form of a job/internship with focus on backend web development in PHP. Available for relocation throughout Brazil or abroad.

## Academic Background

Bachelor's study in Backend Development

Feb 2021 - Present

UNOPAR, Belo Horizonte, Brasil

Master's study in Nanotechnology and Nanomaterials (incomplete)

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Mar 2009 - Feb 2017

SPbU - Saint-Petersburg State University, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Bachelor's Degree in Metallurgical Engineering & Materials

UFOP - Universidade Federal de Ouro Preto, Ouro Preto, Brasil

#### **Portfolio**

#### Bonsai App & API

https://bonsai-app.fly.dev/about

Stack: Laravel, MySQL and Vue.Js; features: API Swagger docs, JWT and UI authentication, webapp in Vue.Js.

#### Transaction API

https://transaction-api.fly.dev/about

Stack: Laravel and SQLite; includes API swagger docs and unitary tests.

#### MVC in Raw PHP

MVC model built in PHP, based on Laravel framework; supports REST API development and file cached memory.

https://github.com/Jadersonrilidio/mvc-architecture-in-php

More projects at Github https://github.com/Jadersonrilidio

### Courses

# Advanced Web Development 2022 in PHP with Laravel and Vue.JS

Sep 2022

Complete Laravel course covering framework functionality and usage, from its architecture and design patterns implementation to integration with Vuejs, Rediscached memory, API development, JWT implementation, Laravel UI auth and more.

#### SQL - Structured Query Language, book 6th edition

Mar 2022

General theory of databases, design and normalization, accompanied by SQL language. (ISBN 8521615582)

# PHP for Beginners, Become a PHP Master - CMS Project

Aug 2021

Practical course in PHP approaching full PHP syntax, procedural and OOP, Composer package management and SQL querying features all included in a CMS project built in PHP with with HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Js and JQuery.

- CSS
- SQL
- Javascript
- Git / Github
- Bootstrap
- Vue.Js
- Python
- Java
- C
- Solidity

## Qualities

- Exceptional at logics and mathematical reasoning
- Eagerness for learning
- Autodidact
- Organized
- Creative
- Proactive

### **Interests**

- Open source technologies
- Network and distributed systems
- Blockchain techlonogy, Solidity & Plutus smart contract
- Tests and automatization

# JavaScript and TypeScript from Basic to Advanced 2020 (incomplete)

JavaScript and TypeScript course from basics to advanced - Modern Javascript (ES6+) for front-end (with Webpack, babel, React, React Hooks, Redux, HTML5, CSS3) and back- end (with Node, Express, MySQL / MariaDB, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Next.Js, Strapi).

#### HTML / CSS - Full Web Development 2019

May 2021

Jun 2021

Review of the chapters referring to HTML 5 and CSS 3 from basic to advanced.

# LPI Linux Essentials: Preparatory Course for Certification

Apr 2021

Course with preparatory content for the LPI Linux Essentials certification exam.

# Solidity - Blockchain Technology Training from Binance

Mar 2021

08- week course focused on blockchain technology and smart contracts creation using the Solidity programming language. Course taught by Binance.

# Programming in Java 11 LTS from Basic to Advanced

Jan 2021

Java course from basics advanced: object orientation, inheritance, polymorphism, collections, threads and data structures (queue, stack, linked lists, etc).

## **Professional Experience**

### VIP Customer Manager

Jul 2019 - Aug 2020

404 Group / Karuna Group, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Meet the needs and provide mentoring for VIP customers from the company's investment branch (in portuguese and english languages), active in the forex trading and binary options markets.

#### Developed skills:

- knowledge of the financial and investment market (currency exchange, stocks, cryptocurrencies, indexes and derivatives);
- Advanced knowledge in portuguese, english and russian languages (portuguese and english for comunication with customers, russian and english for communication among team members and company employees);
- Training and learning of online sales techniques, analysis of customer behavior to choose better approach, problem solving and financial mentoring related to investiments; Basic computer and programming knowledge;
  - Job carried out at the work space and home office.

#### **Bussiness Owner**

Sep 2016 - Jul 2018

Media Finder Publicidade Brasil LTDA - ME, Conselheiro Lafaiete, Minas Gerais, Brasil

Founding partner of the company, responsible for carrying out all relevant tasks for the proper well-functioning, such as:

- Cash flow management;
- Reunions and meetings with customers/partners;
- Documentation and contracts handling;
- Advertising and marketing strategies;
- Product/service logistics.

The company acted for 02 years with the allocation of public spaces for advertisement on public service transport in the city of Conselheiro Lafaiete and its region.

## Academic Experience

### Presentation of Scientific Works

Congresses, Seminars, Conferences, Symposiums

- AISTECH 2013 Pittsburg, PA, United States: Use of Microwave to Produce Charcoal.
- 44th International Steelmaking Seminar 2013 Araxá, Minas Gerais, Brasil: Utilização do Capim Elefante como Fonte de Energia Renovável na Aciaria Elétrica.
- AISTECH 2014 Indianapolis, IN, United States:
   Use of Biomass as Renewable Energy Source in Electric Arc Furnace.
- 53rd School of Condensed State Physics 2019 Saint Petersburg, Russia: Carbon Nanostructures as Nafion Membrane Modifiers: Current Achievements and Challenges.

#### **Publications**

Journals, Periodicals & Congress Proceedings

- Applied Thermal Engineering 2015 an Elsevier Journal: Study of biomass applied to a cogeneration system: A steelmaking industry case. (https://doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2015.01.002)
- SIPS 2015 Antalia, Turkey: Evaluation of Energy Improvement of Gases Generated in Charcoal Production by Microwave.

#### Awards & Achievements

Professional and Personal

- Awarded with the 3rd place at the 'Graduate Studante Poster Contest' held at AISTECH 2014 Conference & Exposition;
- Exchange study in 2017 as master's at the International Economic School, at UrFU Ural Federal University, Yekaterimburg, Russia.